Finding Aid for the Steve Binder Papers PASC.0151
UCLA Library Special Collections
Steve Binder papers
1962-1976
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC.0151
7.0 linear feet (17 boxes)
1.25 linear feet (1 unprocessed flat box)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 997093673606533
Biography
Binder started his entertainment career in 1963; his various television credits include "The Steve Allen Show" (1963-65; 1973), "Hullabaloo" (1965), "Mac Davis" (1978-79), Elvis Presley specials (1968, 1985), and "Pee-Wee's Playhouse" (1987); president Binder Entertainment, Inc., 1986-.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of material related to the career of producer, director and writer Steve Binder. Includes various drafts of scripts, production material, and photographs from a variety of television programs including "The Steve Allen Comedy Hour" (1967), "America Or Bust," "Elvis Presley Special," NBC (1968), "Hullabaloo," "Liza Minnelli Special" (1970), "The Lucy Show" (1966), "The Mac Davis Show" (1976), and "Petula" {Clark} (1968).
Organization
Arranged by television series title.
Television producers and directors -- Archives.; Television writers -- Archives.; Binder, Steve--Archives
- AMERICA OR BUST
  - Starring Glenn Ford, May 1970. First draft, Final draft, includes video tape cue sheets. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mounted photographs. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- ART BUCHWALD'S WASHINGTON
  - "Son of the Great Society." Revised 3/23/66. Director Steven Binder. Includes rundown of show. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- BARRY MANILOW SPECIAL
  - First draft, final draft, and revised final draft. 8/2/76, 8/16/76, 8/19/76. Includes rundown of show. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- DANNY KAYE SHOW, THE
  - Guest stars listed for each show. Scripts and rundowns for shows #65 and #68, Sept, 0ct 1965. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guest stars listed for each show. Scripts and rundowns for shows #69 and #70, September 1965. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- DON KIRSHNER'S ROCK CONCERT
  - Production materials (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scripts for shows #1 & #3, second draft. Annotated. 9/11/73 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scripts for shows #1 & #3. First draft. Annotated. 9/6/73 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- GILLIGAN'S ISLAND
  - "Don't Bug the Mosquitos" and "The Second Ginger Grant." 8/23/65 and 12/12/66. Includes production materials. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- HALLELUJAH LESLIE
  - Scripts. Revised script, 10/26/67. Final script, 11/7/67. Includes cast list. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- HARPER VALLEY, USA
  - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pilot script, first draft. 9/18/69. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Pilot scripts, Final draft. 10/3/69 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pilot scripts, second draft. 9/26/69 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pilot scripts. May, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Production Materials, oversized (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Production notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Talent biographies. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- HOLLYWOOD DEB STAR BALL
  - 14th Annual Deb Star Ball. Script and rundown for the 01/28/67 awards show. Draft date, 01/20/67. Incl. scripts and rundown for Hollywood Stars of Tommorrow Awards. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 13th Annual Ball. Aired 01/07/66. Annotated script and rundown sheets. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- HULLABALOO
  - Mounted photographs. Includes one of Petula Clark as guest performer. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Shows #1, #3, & #4. Scripts. Includes rundowns. Fall 1964 and Winter 1965. NBC. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Shows #5 and #6. Scripts and rundowns. February 1965. NBC. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Shows #7 and #8. February and March, 1965. Scripts and Rundowns. NBC. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- IT'S ABOUT TIME
  - "Cave Family Swingers, The" Two scripts dated 12/15/66 and 12/19/66. Includes Call sheet and annotations. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- JACK PAAR SPECIAL
  - "Funny Thing Happened on the way to the White House." Three scripts. Dated 3/3/66, 5/3/66 (director's master), 5/19/66 (final draft). Includes cast breakdown and rundowns. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- JAZZ SCENE, USA
  - Pilot scripts for two 1/2 hour pilots. Includes production materials. Dated, 3/14/62. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Scripts and production materials for shows #18-26. 1962. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Scripts and production materials for shows #9, #11, & #13. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- LAST LAUGH AT THE SIXTIES, A
  - Correspondence with Steve Binder. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Production materials. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Staring Bob Newhart. Created by Steve Binder. Final Draft. 12/17/69 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Staring Bob Newhart. Created by Steve Binder. Revised Final Draft. 12/19/69. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Staring Bob Newhart. Created by Steve Binder. Treatment and first draft. 12/03/69. Aired 01/08/70. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- LIZA
  - Staring Liza Minnelli. Final Draft. 06/01/70. Annotated. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Staring Liza Minnelli. Music and Lyrics. Includes Correspondence. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Staring Liza Minnelli. Second Draft. 5/25/70. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Staring Liza Minnelli. Treatments. May 1970. Includes First draft. 4/17/70. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- LOLA FALANA
  - Includes Schedules, Cast and Crew sheets, Script, Show info, and set blueprints. January 1976. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- LUCY IN LONDON
  - BOAC airplane photographs. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Staring Lucille Ball. First draft. 05/18/66. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Staring Lucille Ball. Second Draft 05/19/66. Includes Productional Materials and Correspondence. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Staring Lucille Ball. Treatments and continuity script. 05/19/66. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- MAC DAVIS CHRISTMAS SPECIAL, THE
  - "When I Grow Up." Air date 12/15/76. For NBC. Final draft 10/27/76. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- MAC DAVIS SHOW
  - Photographs. Includes publicity still for the Mrs. Miller Sketch. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Production materials. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Show #1. Air date 03/18/76. For NBC. Final Draft. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Show #10. Air date 06/17/76. Final draft. 05/25/76. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Show #2. Air date 03/25/76. For NBC. First draft. 03/10/76. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Show #3. Air date 04/01/76. Final draft. 03/06/76. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Show #5. Air date 04/22/76. Revised final. 03/22/76. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Show #6. Air date 04/29/76. Final draft. 04/21/76. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Show #7. Air date 05/13/76. First draft. 04/26/76. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Show #8. Air date 06/03/76. Final draft. 05/05/76. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Show #9. Air date 06/10/76. Final draft. 05/12/76. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- MAC DAVIS SPECIAL, THE
  - NBC special. Air date 11/13/75. Revised final draft. 10/29/75. (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - "Ask Me a Question" music manuscript by Dotty Wayne, Richard Loring, and Steve Binder, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Directed by Steve Binder" title card, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
- MISSION MAGIC
  - Shows #2 (04/30/73), #3 (05/17/73), #4 (05/25/73), #5 (06/19/73). (Box 13, Folder 3)
- NAACP FREEDOM SPECTACULAR
  - "Some People." Act I script. May 1964. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, news clippings and production materials. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - SOME PEOPLE ad, 1964 May 14 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- NORMAN CORWIN PRESENTS
  - "Two Gods on Prime Time" and "The One Man Show." May-June 1971. Includes legal files. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- PEGGY FLEMMING HOLIDAY ON ICE
  - Produced by Bob Banner. Directed by Steve Binder. Master script. 8/24/76 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- PETULA
  - "Portrait of Petula." Treatment. No date. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Harry Belafonte biography. February 1968. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Petula Clark biographical materials and song lyrics. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photgraphs. Includes photographs of her with Steve Binder. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Staring Petula Clark with Harry Belafonte. Broadcast script. 02/28/68. Air date 04/02/68 at 8 PM on NBC. Includes annotations & inserts. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Staring Petula Clark with Harry Belafonte. First draft. 02/12/68. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- SET THE DATE
  - Production materials and news clippings. 1971. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- STEVE ALLEN COMEDY HOUR, THE
  - Correspondence and production materials. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Show #1. Air date 07/05/67. Aired out of order with taping order. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Show #2. Air date 06/14/67. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Show #3. Air date 06/21/67. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Show #4. Air date 06/28/67. Annotated. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Show #5. Air date 07/19/67. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Show #6. Air date 07/12/67. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Show #7. Air date 08/02/67. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Show #8. Air date 07/26/67. (Box 16, Folder 1)
- T.J.'S
  - Scripts and production materials. 07/13/65. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- TAMI AWARDS, THE
  - Scripts and production materials. October 1964. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- VIKKI CARR SHOW, THE
  - Script, dated 01/20/72. Includes production materials and correspondence. (Box 16, Folder 4)